<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="aa_mode_names">
        <item>None</item>
        <item>1.5 × 1.5 super sampling</item>
        <item>2 × 2 super sampling</item>
        <item>3 × 3 super sampling</item>
        <item>4 × 4 super sampling</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="aa_modes">
        <item>none</item>
        <item>1.5</item>
        <item>2.0</item>
        <item>3.0</item>
        <item>4.0</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="cell_type_abbreviations">
        <item>Pg</item>
        <item>Fl</item>
        <item>Pt</item>
        <item>Dv</item>
        <item>Lp</item>
        <item>Kt</item>
        <item>Bu</item>
        <item>Gl</item>
        <item>Vr</item>
        <item>Ni</item>
        <item>St</item>
        <item>Sn</item>
        <item>My</item>
        <item>Nr</item>
        <item>Sc</item>
        <item>Sm</item>
        <item>Gm</item>
        <item>Cl</item>
        <item>Os</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="cell_type_names">
        <item>Phagocyte</item>
        <item>Flagellocyte</item>
        <item>Photocyte</item>
        <item>Devorocyte</item>
        <item>Lipocyte</item>
        <item>Keratinocyte</item>
        <item>Buoyocyte</item>
        <item>Glueocyte</item>
        <item>Virocyte</item>
        <item>Nitrocyte</item>
        <item>Stereocyte</item>
        <item>Senseocyte</item>
        <item>Myocyte</item>
        <item>Neurocyte</item>
        <item>Secrocyte</item>
        <item>Stemocyte</item>
        <item>Gamete</item>
        <item>Ciliocyte</item>
        <item>Osteocyte</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="cell_type_names_plural">
        <item>Phagocytes</item>
        <item>Flagellocytes</item>
        <item>Photocytes</item>
        <item>Devorocytes</item>
        <item>Lipocytes</item>
        <item>Keratinocytes</item>
        <item>Buoyocytes</item>
        <item>Glueocytes</item>
        <item>Virocytes</item>
        <item>Nitrocytes</item>
        <item>Stereocytes</item>
        <item>Senseocytes</item>
        <item>Myocytes</item>
        <item>Neurocytes</item>
        <item>Secrocytes</item>
        <item>Stemocytes</item>
        <item>Gametes</item>
        <item>Ciliocytes</item>
        <item>Osteocytes</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="challenge_tabs">
        <item>Objective</item>
        <item>Microscope</item>
        <item>Genome</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="language_ids">
        <item>en</item>
        <item>es</item>
        <item>ko</item>
        <item>pl</item>
        <item>ru</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="language_names">
        <item>English</item>
        <item>Español</item>
        <item>한반도 공용어</item>
        <item>Polski</item>
        <item>Русский</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="level_strings">
        <item>Tutorial I</item>
        <item>Introduction to the Microscope</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Tutorial II</item>
        <item>Introduction to the Genome Editor</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Algae</item>
        <item>"Use the genome editor to make a species that thrives in the environment of this challenge.
 
When ready, put a cell on the substrate under the microscope and unfreeze it to see if it is viable. 
100 cells are needed to complete this challenge."</item>
        <item>"The default cell will suffice for this challenge. All cells need energy and the Photocytes available in this challenge get energy from sunlight.
 
Sunlight is incident on the bright area at the top of this substrate."</item>
        <item>Tap on the bright area at the top of the petri dish to add a default cell and change the temperature to observe.</item>
        <item>Algae II</item>
        <item>"This time the objective is to make a species that can multiply to at least 150 cells on the same substrate as the previous challenge.
 
This challenge and many others are not required to proceed in the game. You can solve it at a later point if you find it hard at the moment."</item>
        <item>Smaller cells tend to come in higher numbers. The property Split mass might be useful now.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Algae III</item>
        <item>This substrate has a much lower viscosity than the previous ones. Can you design a species that survives this?</item>
        <item>A useful property in the genome editor is Make adhesin.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Macrophages</item>
        <item>"Another cell type is now available, the Phagocyte. It can eat the small brown dots you might have seen appear when cells die. Eating these pieces of nutrients makes them grow.
 
No light source is present in this challenge, but pieces of nutrients are being sprinkled on the substrate. Can you make a species multiply to 300 cells?"</item>
        <item>Just place a couple Phagocytes with default settings on the substrate and wait and see. In a little while you should have 300 cells.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Macrophages II</item>
        <item>"Can you get 650 cells on the same substrate as before?
 
Now you have access to Flagellocytes in the experimental lab, but in this challenge we still work with the same restrictions as the previous challenge to see if we can optimize our organism without Flagellocytes.
 
You can always skip this challenge and go directly to challenge 9 where you can use Flagellocytes if you like."</item>
        <item>"The properties \"Split angle\" and \"Split mass\" might be useful to solve this challenge. The cells spread more efficiently if they don't end up on a line."</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Colors</item>
        <item>"In this challenge you have 100 h to get 5 red and 5 yellow cells. Only problem, you can not place any cells. You do, however, have access to the cell boost tool. This tool lets you make cells grow and split.
 
Can you figure out which cells to boost to get the correct number of cells of each color?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Breeding</item>
        <item>"We have found a beautiful, and tasty, red cell in nature. We would like to have more of it to improve the institute canteen but since it has a strict no-GMO policy, we cannot recreate this by copying it to the genome editor. 
Can you make more of this cell using some traditional breeding strategy?"</item>
        <item>Use the move tool to help this cell</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Coexistence</item>
        <item>Can you get over 400 cells during 50 h on this substrate by just adding one initial cell?</item>
        <item>You will need your initial cell to divide into two cells with different functions.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Tutorial III</item>
        <item>Introduction to Genetic Design</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Macrophages III</item>
        <item>"We are going to try to use your new cell, the Flagellocyte, for this challenge. This cell can not gain energy from the environment, but it can swim! Note that this cell immediately dies if attached to another cell such that the flagellum is obstructed.
 
The viscosity of this substrate is higher than in the previous \"Macrophages\" challenge. Can you nevertheless make a species multiply to 420 cells?"</item>
        <item>"To solve this challenge you will need your organism's life cycle to include three different modes.
 
Ticking \"Contaminate with random cells\" in experimental mode and running for a little while might give you some ideas on how to solve this challenge."</item>
        <item>"Have mode 1 split to mode 2 and 3. 
Have mode 3 split to 3 and 1. 
Let mode 1 and 3 be Phagocytes and mode 2 Flagellocyte. 
Tick \"Make Adhesin\" for mode 1.
 
Note that this is one among many different ways to solve this challenge."</item>
        <item>Macrophages IV</item>
        <item>"The environment of this challenge is less friendly than the previous one. Can you nevertheless get 300 cells?
 
This requires some serious optimization of your cells. Note that all challenges do not have to be solved to progress in the game."</item>
        <item>"Having trouble solving some of the challenges and need some inspiration? Let evolution do the job for you! Go to the \"Challenges\" tab of the main menu and make a long press on this challenge to open it in experimental mode. Put the solution you found for the Macrophages III challenge on the substrate (you can save and load genomes in the genome editor).
 
Now start the simulation and you should have some cells multiplying in the environment. If you now increase the radiation level from 0 to slightly above 0 the cells will start mutating and soon you will have more cells than you started with since they have adapted to their environment. Once they reach the required limit you can copy a cell to the genome editor, save it, and use it in this challenge."</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Sunlight</item>
        <item>The light source is now moving around the substrate, much like the sun. Your goal is to design cells that can multiply up to 130 cells with this rotating light source.</item>
        <item>You will need to make a cell that can swim around the edge of the substrate, following the light. Maybe you can modify your solution of challenge \"Macrophages III\" slightly?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Scavenger</item>
        <item>The only source of energy on this substrate is the sun. Can you nevertheless create a viable species without using photocytes?</item>
        <item>The present photocytes leave small pieces of nutrients behind when they die. Can you make a species that lives off of them?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Seed</item>
        <item>"A new type of cell is now available, the Lipocyte. This cell contains fat and can thus store more energy than other cells. These cells also consume very little energy.
 
This substrate contains no energy source, can you nevertheless keep 16 live cells on it for 50 h?"</item>
        <item>Use a Lipocyte with very low split mass and just wait.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Sunlight II</item>
        <item>The light source is now moving faster. Your goal is to design cells that can multiply up to 500 cells with this itinerant light source.</item>
        <item>Your cells can never swim fast enough to keep up with the sun. Instead, accumulate energy when it is abundant for use during dark times.</item>
        <item>"Make a long worm consisting of both Photocytes and Lipocytes. One way is to have:
 
Mode 1: Photocyte, split to 2,3 
Mode 2: Lipocyte, will not split 
Mode 3: Photocyte, split to 1,1
 
Make adhesin for all of them."</item>
        <item>Macrophages V</item>
        <item>Cells now die when they reach the edge of the substrate. Can you make a species maintaining a cell count above 150 for 100 h?</item>
        <item>"Having trouble solving some of the challenges and need some inspiration? Let evolution do the job for you! Go to the \"Challenges\" tab of the main menu and make a long press on this challenge to open it in experimental mode. Put the solution you found for the Macrophages III challenge on the substrate (you can save and load genomes in the genome editor).
 
Now start the simulation and you should have some cells multiplying in the environment. If you now increase the radiation level from 0 to slightly above 0 the cells will start mutating and soon you will have more cells than you started with since they have adapted to their environment. Once they reach the required limit you can copy a cell to the genome editor, save it, and use it in this challenge."</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Decimation</item>
        <item>Your research team has developed a new type of cell that you need to test. The Devorocyte sucks nutrients from other cells upon touching them. Can you decrease the number of cells in this substrate to below 300?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Breeding II</item>
        <item>Our micropipette is under maintenance so we can not insert new cells at the moment. Can you anyways get 100 red cells on this Petri dish?</item>
        <item>There is some mutagen present on this substrate, use it to your advantage.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Infestation</item>
        <item>You forgot a sample in the incubator for a week and some new species developed. They spread spores very efficiently and infested all your samples. Can you devise a method to remove them?</item>
        <item>Spend more time using the microscope than engineering a genome.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Countermeasure</item>
        <item>"Your collaborators have been able to develop a cell immune to attacks from your Devorocytes. The Keratinocyte can defend itself and cells attached directly to it from hostile cells.
 
Can you help them design an organism able to disrupt the ecosystem living on this plate? They want at least 420 cells."</item>
        <item>Make a swimming organism consisting of three cells, a Keratinocyte in the center, a Flagellocyte in the rear, and a Phagocyte in the front.</item>
        <item>"Let mode 1, 3 and 5 be Phagocytes, mode 2 Flagellocyte, and finally mode 4 a Keratinocyte. 
Tick \"Make Adhesin\" for mode 1 and 3.
 
Have mode 1 split to mode 2 and 3 (in that order). Now we have an ordinary swimmer. 
Have mode 3 split to 4 and 5. Now we have an immune swimmer. 
Have mode 5 split to 5 and 1. Now we release eggs for new swimmers.
 
Note that this is one among many different ways to solve this challenge."</item>
        <item>Conquering</item>
        <item>"Remove all the red cells! You need your cells to survive at least 30 h after the red cells died to make sure your cells can survive on their own.

This challenge must be solved within 220 h."</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Floaters</item>
        <item>A new cell is available. The Buoyocyte has a compartment that can contain a liquid of a different density than other cells. See if you can use it to create life on this substrate which has been oriented vertically so that cells are slowly sinking to the bottom of it. 350 cells should indicate that they can live and reproduce.</item>
        <item>You will need to lower the density setting of your Buoyocytes.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Floaters II</item>
        <item>Now the substrate is still oriented vertically but the material of the substrate is of a density close to the density of the cells so they do not fall. Can you make a species that multiplies to 400 cell without using Flagellocytes?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Parasite</item>
        <item>"The density of this slippery substrate varies with height, making cells collect in the center.
 
Some species is already living here but can you get another one living here for at least 500h without using phagocytes?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Sterilization</item>
        <item>You need to kill all cells on this substrate but lost your bottle of sterilizer, you have to think of something else.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Mosh pit</item>
        <item>Can you make an organism quickly take over this crowded substrate?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Slippery Slope</item>
        <item>In this sample, viscosity is nonexistent. Can you make an organism capable of surviving and thriving in these harsh conditions?</item>
        <item>Try to make your organism stick to the lit area using the Glueocyte.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Sterilization II</item>
        <item>Some kind of worm-like organism has attached itself to the top of our substrate. We need to get it rid of it so we can use the Petri dish for our next experiment.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Moss IVF</item>
        <item>"We here have a moss sperm and a moss egg that we want to fertilize for our moss breeding program.
 
The sperm is able to avoid black cells but not the red ones. Can you help it reach the egg?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Floaters III</item>
        <item>Can you figure out what substrate this is and get 450 cells to live on it?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Harsh Conditions</item>
        <item>"In this sample there are no nitrates in the substrate. Though a new cell which can bind nitrogen, the Nitrocyte, is now available. This cell can supply connected cells with nitrates. Any cell can store a rather large amount of nitrates so they need not be connected to this cell. Cells do not consume the nitrates, though they are shared between the daughter cells when a cell divides. If a cell does not have enough nitrates to divide into two cells, it simply will not divide.
 
Can you make an organism able to multiply into 200 cells in this environment?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Harsh Conditions II</item>
        <item>No sun this time. Can you get 400 cells?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Symbiosis</item>
        <item>"Most plants in the legume family live in symbiosis with nitrogen fixating bacteria called rhizobia living in their root systems. The bacteria provides nitrogen to the plants while the plants provide nutrients to the bacteria.
 
On this substrate we have a couple of very tiny plants of the legume family. Unfortunately their rhizobia was killed by a virus and the plants as a result have stopped growing due to lack of nitrogen.
 
Can you design some new organisms to take the role of the rhizobia?"</item>
        <item>Glueocytes can help transfer nutrients between different species.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Slippery Slope II</item>
        <item>Can you get 700 cells on this peculiar substrate?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Infection</item>
        <item>"The Virocyte is a cell infected with a virus. If another cell touches this cell it risks also getting infected unless it is protected by a Keratinocyte. Part of this cells genome will get copied into the other cell when it gets infected. This is very much how a virus works in nature.
 
Which part of the genome gets copied is specified by the \"Virus copy from\" property in the genome editor. Note that not only the genes for one mode are copied but also the genes for the modes of 2 generations of descendants. So a maximum of 1+2+4 modes of the host genome are copied to the newly infected cell.
 
In this challenge you are supposed to kill all the initial cells by infecting them with a virus and leave the substrate clean."</item>
        <item>Tap on a cell under the microscope and press \"Load\" in the Genome editor and select \"Load from microscope\" to inspect the organisms living on this substrate before designing a virus.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Maze</item>
        <item>"As part of our labs public outreach initiative we are attempting to set the world record for the smallest maze.
 
Can you test it to make sure it works?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Infection II</item>
        <item>Viruses are often specifically evolved to infect a certain host. Can you make a virus infecting these organisms leaving the substrate clean?</item>
        <item>Tap on a cell under the microscope and press \"Load\" in the Genome editor and select \"Load from microscope\" to inspect the organisms living on this substrate before designing a virus.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Noncommutative viruses</item>
        <item>"The order of infection is important when different viruses overwrites the same part of a cells genome.
 
These viruses have been designed to create an interesting organism by infecting a simple lipocyte. Their order has been messed up, can you figure out the correct order of infection?"</item>
        <item>In the main settings of cell lab there is an option to show cell types next to mode names. Turning that on is useful to inspect the genomes of these viruses.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Infection III</item>
        <item>The objective is once again to remove all the cells from the substrate, which now does not contain any nitrates.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Gene Therapy</item>
        <item>"Gene therapy is a method practiced in medicine to correct a defective genome by inserting new genes. The new genes are typically inserted using a virus as a vector. A special virus is prepared that does not cause much harm but inserts a missing gene.
 
On this substrate we have some particularly ugly cells, specifically, mother nature did a very bad job of matching the color of the Phagocyte to the color of the Flagellocyte. We don't have access to the Flagellocyte genes but would like some more visually appealing swimmers than these. Could you do some gene therapy on these cells to obtain about the same number of swimmers but in a color scheme of your liking instead? They need to survive more than 200 h."</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Digestion</item>
        <item>"You've run out of the ordinary nutrients for your cells. In desperation to feed them you saved a piece of bacon from lunch but now realize your phagocytes can not feed on fat.
 
Luckily, the researchers in the molecular biology lab have already been working on a similar scenario and were able to develop Secrocytes that produce Lipase, an enzyme that can break down fat into fatty acids that the phagocytes can eat."</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Digestion II</item>
        <item>"An engineered organisms used to make biofuel from sunlight is living on this Petri dish.
 
Can you make an organism living off of the lipids that are released from the dying lipocytes and thus ruining our production?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Population Bottleneck</item>
        <item>"This diverse ecosystem reproduces sexually using a new cell type, the gamete. This cell doesn't have a complete set of chromosomes and can thus not split.
 
However, it can fuse with another compatible gamete to form a new cell with complete genome. After fusing the mode is changed and the lifecycle can continue. This way beneficial traits can efficiently spread through a population.
 
The ecosystem on this dish unfortunately went through a population bottleneck when professor Challenger spilled a mug of coffee on it. Now the gene for swimming fast is missing. Can you reintroduce it to the gene pool?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Adaptation</item>
        <item>"You have been experimenting with a swimming Photocyte organism. Unfortunately, your light system started malfunctioning and is now rotating slowly.
 
Your organism is not fit enough to keep up. You have to introduce it to a new diet in order to keep it alive!"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Paleogenetics</item>
        <item>"This ancient green organism was found living in an acidic lake. Archaeologists have in the same lake found microscopic fossils of a—now extinct—predator species thought to once live off of these green creatures. To corroborate this theory we would like to see if there are some traces of their interaction left in the genome of the green species. To test our theory we have placed a synthetic predator species on this substrate to see if some protective mechanism can be awoken from the depths of the green swimmers genome. That didn't happen.
 
Upon inspection of the genome we have found that a recent mutation has taken a shortcut, the M3 cells no longer split to M5,M6, but it splits to M3,M4. Perhaps this mutation proliferated as a result of the extinction of the predator? Anyhow, can you—without inserting a keratinocyte—restore the old behavior and see what the species does in this synthetic environment?
 
If you get 400 cells without actually introducing a keratinocyte then we have confirmed that this species has genes to protect itself from the predator and thus the fossil predators were most likely once living off of this organism."</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Tip the Balance</item>
        <item>Three species are living on this substrate. Can you make them all die?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Keep the Balance</item>
        <item>Two species are living on this substrate. Can you add a third?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Tutorial IV</item>
        <item>Introduction to Cell Signaling</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Balloons</item>
        <item>"Our politicians have introduced patent laws to help foster technological advancements.
 
We can now not use the solution to Floaters II anymore without paying a huge license fee for the Buoyocytes. Our budget now only allows for one Buoyocyte per genome and we can thus not make an equally efficient species anymore.
 
We have had to lower our ambitions for this substrate to 200 cells. Can you work around the limitations posed by the patent laws by using the Neurocyte?"</item>
        <item>Use the longest time on the oscillator preset. Make sure to set the Neurocyte adhesin connections to what the case is in your organism.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Friction</item>
        <item>This substrate has dried up a bit and swimming is not very efficient any more. Can you use the recently developed Myocyte to find another means of locomotion?</item>
        <item>The muscle contract and lift properties are useful here. Perhaps assign them to different channels.</item>
        <item>Make a three-celled linear organism with a Myocyte in the center. Setting the split ratio and mass in a good way is crucial.</item>
        <item>Nervous</item>
        <item>"Our field biologists have found a tiny organism that exhibits a defence behaviour when subject to a certain stimulus.
 
Can you figure out what the stimulus is?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Friction II</item>
        <item>This substrate is even drier, and the cell limits are higher. Can you still make it?</item>
        <item>Making a slightly easier version of this substrate and using evolution can help you solve this. Let it run for a night :)</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Scarce Conditions</item>
        <item>"We now have access to two new cells, Senseocyte and the Sterocyte. They can sense smell from either food or cells of certain colors. The Senseocyte will output a signal substance based on the smell molecule concentration. The Stereocyte will output a signal substance based on the left-right concentration gradient of smell molecules.
 
Food is now very scarce, can you figure out a way to survive on this substrate?"</item>
        <item>Use the Stereocyte and Myocyte for steering towards food. Think about the placement of the cells within your organism.</item>
        <item>"Make a simple swimmer so that once it gets enough food it will split into a four-celled linear organism, Flagellocyte-Myocyte-Stereocyte-Phagocyte. Make the Myocyte bend according to the smell direction picked up by the Stereocyte.
 
Tuning the Myocyte response is crucial and requires some experimenting.
 
Let the Phagocyte split off the simple swimmers that will sometimes be lucky and develop into these four-celled navigating swimmers and thus letting your organism reproduce.
 
Setting the adhesin strength high and tuning the split masses is crucial
 
Note that this is one of many ways of solving this challenge."</item>
        <item>Scarce Conditions II</item>
        <item>Can you make a species survive here without using the Myocyte?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Flat Earth</item>
        <item>"This Petri dish is slippery and has no rim so cells fall and die when they reach the edge.
 
Can you nevertheless get 300 cells?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Scarce Conditions III</item>
        <item>Can you optimize an organism to get 600 cells on this substrate?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Digestion III</item>
        <item>This challenge is similar to Digestion, but here food is more scarce.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Predator</item>
        <item>Can you make a predator reproduce to 50 cells and lower the prey population to 300 cells?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Deception</item>
        <item>"Now we have access to the Secrocyte. This cell can secrete different molecules to its surrounding.
 
Can you make a parasitic organism live off of these harvesting organisms?"</item>
        <item>The Glueocyte is useful here. Giving your organism some mobility might be helpful.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Food delivery</item>
        <item>"The red predator doesn't have any food nearby. Can you deliver it to it?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Move it!</item>
        <item>"This substrate has high salinity and very low viscosity with huge nutrient chunks. A paradise for smart swimmers. Alas, we cannot use Flagellocytes.
 
Can you still make an organism thriving in this environment?"</item>
        <item>A technique we call mitotic propulsion is useful here.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Extermination</item>
        <item>Some mine-laying organism is living on this plate. Can you give them a taste of their own medicine and leave the plate clean afterwards?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Discrimination</item>
        <item>"On this plate we have two similar species.
Can you eradicate the red one while keeping the blue one alive? Don't leave any of your own cells on the plate when you are done."</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Avoidance</item>
        <item>Can you make a species reproduce to 150 cells while keeping the initial cell count low for 100 h?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Avoidance II</item>
        <item>Can you make a species reproduce to 200 cells while keeping the initial cell count low for 200 h? Now the initial cells are moving.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Nanobot</item>
        <item>"We have a skin sample from a patient with skin cancer. 
Can you engineer an organism that can remove the cancer cells but keep the rest of the skin intact?"</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Desert</item>
        <item>This substrate is all dried up and also has almost no food. Can you get 200 cells?</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item>Desert II</item>
        <item>Same plate but now 600 cells.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="log_interval_names">
        <item>No logging</item>
        <item>Every 12 min</item>
        <item>Every 1 h</item>
        <item>Every 5 h</item>
        <item>Every 25 h</item>
        <item>Every 125 h</item>
        <item>Every 625 h</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="log_intervals">
        <item>none</item>
        <item>12m</item>
        <item>1h</item>
        <item>5h</item>
        <item>25h</item>
        <item>125h</item>
        <item>625h</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="modes">
        <item>Freeze</item>
        <item>Observe</item>
        <item>Incubate</item>
        <item>Slow observe</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="play_tabs">
        <item>Substrate</item>
        <item>Microscope</item>
        <item>Genome</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="tut_text_1">
        <item>"Two tutorials are provided to make you familiar with our lab equipment. Safety procedures will be taught another day.
 
This first tutorial will teach you how to use our microscope.
 
Please start by moving to the microscope."</item>
        <item>"Good job!
 
What you see here is a Petri dish we have prepared for you.
 
To zoom with this microscope do an inverse pinch with two fingers.
 
Please increase the magnification to 300×."</item>
        <item>"Great!
 
Now move the substrate so that we are looking at the brighter area at the top of the Petri dish where sunlight is visible. Zoom so that this area covers the screen.
 
Swipe with one finger to move the substrate."</item>
        <item>"I see you have used a microscope before!
 
This microscope is equipped with a micromanipulator. One of its uses is to insert cells from our genetics lab on the substrate.
 
Can you insert one of our recently developed cells in the area with sunlight?
 
Tap where you want to insert the cell."</item>
        <item>"Not too hard!
 
Our microscope also has a system for controlling the temperature of the substrate. Turn up the temperature to the \"Observe\" setting where the cells live but move slowly.
 
The temperature setting is chosen by the selector in the top right."</item>
        <item>"Now you should see the cells multiplying, otherwise insert a couple more in the bright area.
 
We want to incubate the substrate for a while so our cells attain an equilibrium.
 
Increase the temperature to the \"Incubate\" setting."</item>
        <item>"Now you should have a lot of cells!
 
This makes it hard to keep track of them but luckily the microscope has a visual tracker. The tracker overlays a marker on a selected cell and also moves the substrate to keep it in view.
 
Set temperature to \"Observe\" again and tap on a cell to tell the microscope to track it."</item>
        <item>"Good!
 
Sometimes we bring in cells from nature, or our noses, to study. We can then extract their DNA using the micropipette to study it in the genome editor. Let's do that on one of the cells on the substrate right now.
 
We put a mutagen in the substrate so some cells should have mutated. Pick an interesting one and tell the tracker to follow it. Freeze the substrate before doing this."</item>
        <item>"Good job. Next step is to go to the genome editor, tap \"GENOME\" and press \"load\".
 
There choose \"Load from microscope\" and the micropipette will automatically extract the DNA of the cell in the tracker, sequence it, and send it in digitized form to the genome editor.
"</item>
        <item>"Great! Now we have the genome of the mutated cell in the genome editor.
 
Your last task is to sterilize the substrate with the built-in autoclave to prepare for the next experiment. This is done using the reset button at the top (a petri dish with an orange arrow).
 
Good luck and keep your fingers out of the autoclave!"</item>
        <item>"You have now completed the microscope training program. Next up is the genome editor training program.
 
Press the back arrow to exit this first tutorial."</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="tut_text_2">
        <item>"This tutorial will guide you through how to use the genome editor.
 
Please start by going to the genome editing lab."</item>
        <item>"Good!
 
What you see here is the genome editor. It is divided in two parts: 
\u0009- The preview window. 
\u0009- The mode editor
 
We will start off by introducing the preview window. It shows you your organism at a certain age.
 
The slider right below the preview is used to set at what age you would like to view your organism.
 
Now set the preview to show your organism at age 2.0 h."</item>
        <item>"Good job!
 
That is all we need to know about the preview for now. Now some genetics!
 
All cells in the human body have the same DNA, but muscle and brain cells behave very differently. This is referred to as different&lt;i> modes&lt;/i> of a cell in our lab.
 
The genome editor can handle 40 different modes. Each mode has its own properties.
 
One mode is edited at a time in the genome editor and to change what mode is currently being edited we use the selector \"Edit mode\".
 
Now let's edit the mode called M5."</item>
        <item>"Now all properties you see below the selector you just used describe properties of mode M5. You might wonder, what mode are the cells in the preview in?
 
They are in mode M1 because M1 is by default the initial mode. What mode is initial just tells the preview what mode to start with.
 
Now make M5 initial instead by pressing the radio button \"Initial\"."</item>
        <item>"Nice work!
 
There are a lot of different properties in each mode, more than we can go through in this tutorial. This means you will have to explore them yourself. If you want more information about any setting in the genome editor then just click on the accompanying text with an underline.
 
Now read the text about the property \"Red color\". You might have to scroll down to see it."</item>
        <item>"Good job!
 
Now find two more properties and make your mode M5 cells completely red."</item>
        <item>"Very beautiful!
 
If you drag the preview time slider back and forth you see your cells dividing. Many settings control how the divisions take place.
 
Two important settings are what modes the two daughter cells are in. These settings are labeled \"Child 1: mode\" and \"Child 2: mode\".
 
Set them so that when a mode M5 cell splits: 
\u0009- Child 1 is of mode M6 
\u0009- Child 2 is of mode M7."</item>
        <item>"Good job!
 
You should now see two different cells, one in M6 and one in M7.
 
Increase the preview time to 4 h to see what these cells split into."</item>
        <item>"Good job!
 
You should now see 4 cells. Two in mode M6 on the left and two in mode M7 on the right. The family tree looks like:
 
\u0009\u0009      5           time: 0.0 h 
\u0009\u0009    /  \\ 
\u0009\u0009   6    7        time: 2.0 h 
\u0009\u0009 / \\    / \\ 
\u0009\u00096  6  7  7    time: 4.0 h
 
Now change the family tree into
 
\u0009\u0009      5 
\u0009\u0009    /  \\ 
\u0009\u0009   6    7 
\u0009\u0009 / \\    / \\ 
\u0009\u00095  5  5  5
 
by setting the \"Child 1: mode=M5\" and \"Child 2: mode=M5\" of mode M6 and M7.
 
Tip: Instead of changing the selector \"Edit mode\", you can tap on cells in the preview to change what mode to edit."</item>
        <item>"Good job!
 
Now your initial M5 cell splits into an M6 and an M7 cell. They will further split into two M5 cells each and the life cycle is complete.
 
Now place one of these cells in the microscope and see how you get three types of cells, but all with the same genomes."</item>
        <item>"Excellent work!
 
You have now finished the genome editor tutorial and you are certified to work in our lab!
 
Good luck with your research!"</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="tut_text_3">
        <item>"This tutorial will guide you through how to design a basic swimming and reproducing organism.
 
First go to the genome editor and make sure that mode M1 is of type Phagocyte and makes adhesin when it splits. Then set the preview time to 0.8 h."</item>
        <item>"Nice work!
 
Remember that you can press the Make adhesin text to understand what that property is.
 
Now you should see two identical cells attached to each other. They are both in mode M1 since the initial cell in mode M1 currently splits into two cells of the same mode.
 
Now we want to modify this so that the left cell is in mode M2 and the right is in mode M3. 
We do this by editing mode M1: 
Set child 1: mode to M2 
Set child 2: mode to M3"</item>
        <item>"Excellent!
 
Now you should see two cells of different colors. 
We want the left cell to propel our organism and the right cell to provide it with energy. 
Make sure mode M3 is a Phagocyte. 
Then edit mode M2 and make it a Flagellocyte."</item>
        <item>"Great!
 
You now have a swimmer! You can try that it actually swims in the microscope.
 
It can not reproduce yet though. We want the Phagocyte in the front to split off a spore that can develop into a new swimmer. 
We thus do not want the Flagellocyte to ever split so go to mode M2 and set the split mass to max."</item>
        <item>"Great!
 
Now you can turn up the preview time to 2.0 h. 
We see a spore splits off from the mode M3 cell. We want this spore to be of the initial mode M1 so the life cycle is closed.
 
Edit mode M3 and set Child 2 to be of mode M1."</item>
        <item>"Perfect!
 
Your swimmer should be done now! You can try it out in the microscope. It is a good idea to save this genome for future use in the challenges."</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="tut_text_4">
        <item>"In this tutorial we learn the basics of cell signaling.
 
We have 4 different cell signaling molecules at our disposal. We call these S1, S2, S3 and S4.
 
The behavior of some cells are affected by the concentrations of these within the cell. In Cell Lab we refer to the affected behaviors as&lt;i> programmable&lt;/i>. Some types of cells produce these signaling molecules. One of them is the Neurocyte.
 
Let M1 be a Neurocyte and let it split into a basic two-celled swimmer: 
M1 = Neurocyte, make adhesin 
\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009\u0009child 1 = M2, child 2 = M3 
M2 = Flagellocyte 
M3 = Phagocyte"</item>
        <item>"Nice work!
 
The Swim force of the Flagellocytes is a programmable property. Next to the Swim force-slider there is now a button with an ellipsis (…) on it. Press this button."</item>
        <item>"You found it :)
 
Here you can set the swim force to depend on the cell state instead of being a fixed value. In particular, set the input to be signal substance&lt;b> S1&lt;/b>.
 
There are two types of dependences on the input, a linear function and a step function.
 
Choose the first equation which is the linear dependence. This only depends on the parameters a and b. Set a=4 and b=0.
 
Now the swim force will be high when the S1 concentration is high, and low when the S1 concentration is low."</item>
        <item>"Great!
 
Let us now try out this swimmer by setting the substrate to Observe and then placing one of the M1 Neurocytes in it."</item>
        <item>"You should see your initial Neurocyte split into a swimmer, but it shouldn't swim at all. This is because the S1 concentration is 0.
 
We want our M1 Neurocyte to produce some S1. Neurocytes have four different pathways for producing signal substances. Each can be set to produce any of the four signal substances.
 
Go to the mode M1 settings and look at the end. You will see a list of output settings. These settings are, just like the swim force, also programmable. For now we use a fixed value. Set the first channel to S1 and increase the first output amount to max.
 
Now again place the M1 Neurocyte on your substrate."</item>
        <item>"Cool!
 
Your swimmer should now have been swimming for a short while and then stopped. The reason it stops is because the signal molecules left over from the initial Neurocyte decay. This means the concentration quickly goes to 0 if they aren't continuously being produced.
 
Let us change the head of the swimmer (M3) to a Neurocyte. Then go to the output settings of M3 and press the oscillator preset button."</item>
        <item>"This preset will set the four output pathways in a clever way such that the concentrations of two signal substances will start to oscillate.
 
Indicate 1 Neurocyte adhesin connection since your Neurocyte has one connection and set channels to S1 and S2 and set the period to 1 hour. Now put an M1 Neurocyte onto the substrate again and see how the swimmer behaves!"</item>
        <item>"You should now see your cell swim and stop, swim and stop, and so on until it dies. Pretty neat! The signal molecules from the Neurocyte diffuse through the adhesin connection to the Flagellocyte. This happens for all cells except for Lipocytes. Lipocytes can therefore be used similarly to how glial cells function in animals.
 
You have now finished the tutorial and are ready for some neuroscience!"</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="tut_title_1">
        <item>Welcome to Cell Lab!</item>
        <item>Changing Magnification</item>
        <item>Navigation</item>
        <item>Micropipette</item>
        <item>Temperature</item>
        <item>Incubation</item>
        <item>Cell tracking</item>
        <item>DNA extraction</item>
        <item>DNA extraction</item>
        <item>Sterilization</item>
        <item>Congratulations!</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="tut_title_2">
        <item>Welcome!</item>
        <item>Overview</item>
        <item>Cell Modes</item>
        <item>Initial Mode</item>
        <item>Property Descriptions</item>
        <item>Finding Properties</item>
        <item>Child Modes</item>
        <item>Grandchild Modes</item>
        <item>Close the Circle</item>
        <item>Insert into Microscope</item>
        <item>Congratulations!</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="tut_title_3">
        <item>Welcome to the genetic design tutorial!</item>
        <item>Setting cell generation 1</item>
        <item>Setting cell types of generation 1</item>
        <item>Stop propulsion cell from splitting</item>
        <item>Close the circle</item>
        <item>Save your work</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="tut_title_4">
        <item>Welcome to the cell signaling tutorial!</item>
        <item>Program swim force</item>
        <item>Set dependence</item>
        <item>Test it!</item>
        <item>Produce some S1</item>
        <item>Use preset</item>
        <item>Oscillating neurocyte</item>
        <item>Tutorial finished!</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
